Wenda Qiu

⊠ qiuwenda@sjtu.edu.cn

Objective

I am an undergraduate student from Shanghai Jiao Tong University (SJTU) ACM Honors Class, Zhiyuan College (an honors college) and major in computer science. I have a great passion on my major and science research and I hope I can devote myself to this career in the future.

Education

2015.9–2019.6 **Bachelor of Science**, Computer Science.

(Anticipated) Shanghai Jiao Tong University ACM Honors Class, Zhiyuan College

Experience

2018.7-2018.12

University of Research Assistant guided by Prof. Jiawei Han.

Illinois at Urbana- I worked as a visiting research assistant at University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign un-Champaign, der the instruction of Prof. Jiawei Han since July 2018. My research topic is about text data mining.

Synonym Set Expansion

Synonym detection and semantic set expansion are fundamental tasks for many applications.

- o I tried to improve the exisiting method for semantic set expansion, both in performance and efficiency.
- o I also helped design a framework to combine the 2 tasks to mutually enhance each other by a feedback loop to strengthen the original seeds iteratively.
- I played a roll as the co-first author in the paper in preparation for the coming conference.

Shanghai Jiao Research Assistant guided by Prof. Hongtao Lu.

Tong University, I worked as a research assistant at Shanghai Jiao Tong University advised by Prof. Hongtao Lu. 2017.7-2018.6 My research topic is image-to-image networks belongs to computer vision field.

• Image to image translation

Image to image translation is an impressive application of generative models.

- I surveyed and implemented different generative models.
- I praticed my basic skills such as python and pytorch programming.

Shanghai Jiao Shanghai Jiao Tong University ACM-ICPC Team Member.

2015.6-2017.5

Tong University, I have joined SJTU ACM-ICPC (a world-wide team-based computer problem solving competition) group since summer of 2015.

> My team represented Shanghai Jiao Tong University in the ACM-ICPC World Finals 2017 and 2018. Our strong teamwork ensured us a deserved champion in Asia Tsukuba reginal 2016.

2017.6-2018.4

Shanghai Jiao Shanghai Jiao Tong University ACM-ICPC Team Leader.

Tong University, I served as the leader for representative team of our university. We stood out in regional contests and won the qualification to participate in ACM-ICPC World Finals 2018.

As the most senior student in the team, I brought all my experiences into play and our team achieved a silver medal in the World Final 2018.

Awards

- 2018.4 ACM-ICPC World Final 2018, 8th Place, Silver Medal.
- 2017.5 ACM-ICPC World Final 2017. 13th Place.
- 2017.11 The 2017 ACM-ICPC Asia Beijing Regional Contest, 2nd Place, Gold Medal.

2016.10 The 2016 ACM-ICPC Asia Tsukuba Regional, 1st Place, Gold Medal, Champion.

ACM-ICPC stands for ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest. You may find a full list of my ICPC awards at icpc.baylor.edu/ICPCID/TSIL76L1GG4Y.

2016, 2017 **Zhiyuan Honorary Scholarship**, *SJTU top 5%*.

Zhiyuan College offers an honors program to selected students among SJTU Top 5% undergraduate students.

2014.7 National Olympiad in Informatics of China, Silver Medal.

Manuscripts

KDD

In preparation for Synonym-aware set expansion

Projects

Advanced Data This is a group project for data structure course. We implemented Y-Fast-Trie: a structure Structure storing integers from a bounded domain, Dominitor Tree: a structure finding dominators in control flow graphs, and Rank-pairing-Heap: a priority queue works $O(\log n)$ amortized time in delete-min operation and O(1) in others. Score: 95/100

MIPS CPU This is a course project for computer architecture: a simulation for CPU with five-stage MIPS pipeline. The environment I use is Verilog. Score: 90/100

Benchmark for This is a computer vision course group project. A VQA (Visual Question Answering) system VQA generates answers according to the given scenes and a natural language question. We try to propose a method to evaluate how much a VQA system makes visual reasoning rather than exploiting biases. Score: 88/100

Attack on This is a group project for neural network research course given by John Hopcroft. We study Img2Img Networks the robustness of neural networks and carry out experiments generating slightly changed adversarial examples to fool an img2img network into faked results. Score: 90/100

Visual Dynamics

This is a vitual reality course project, which has a close connection with computer vision. In this task, our group studied and made improvement in visual dynamics using disentangled manners and convolutional networks. Score: 93/100

Skills

Programming C++, Python, Java

Languages

Frameworks Pytorch

English level Fluent (TOEFL iBT 104/120)